Guide to the William Robinson Brown Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Robinson Brown papers
1907-1958
MS 107
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
(20 boxes)
Business correspondence, articles, speeches, and the manuscripts of Brown's book, Our Forest Heritage: a History of Forestry and Recreation in New Hampshire (1958), forestry studies, and Congressional bills. Includes papers relating to the Brown Company of Berlin, New Hampshire (manufacturer of paper products, chemicals, and other wood-using products), the American Forestry Association, New Hampshire Disaster Emergency Council, New Hampshire Forestry Commission, North East Forest Research Council, Society for the Protection of New Hampshire Forests, Society of American Foresters, and the Timber Lands Mutual Insurance Company.
Brown, William Robinson, 1875-1955
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Henry I. Baldwin, 1967.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Topical Files. III. Manuscripts.
Biographical / Historical
Chairman of the New Hampshire Forestry and Recreation Commission, 1910-1952; active in various forestry organizations in the 1930s; author.
Scope and Contents
Business correspondence, articles, speeches, and the manuscripts of Brown's book, Our Forest Heritage: a History of Forestry and Recreation in New Hampshire (1958), forestry studies, and Congressional bills. Includes papers relating to the Brown Company of Berlin, New Hampshire (manufacturer of paper products, chemicals, and other wood-using products), the American Forestry Association, New Hampshire Disaster Emergency Council, New Hampshire Forestry Commission, North East Forest Research Council, Society for the Protection of New Hampshire Forests, Society of American Foresters, and the Timber Lands Mutual Insurance Company.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Forests and forestry; World War, 1914-1918; New England; New Hampshire -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Businessmen; Foresters; Allen, E. T. (Edward Tyson), 1875-1942; Ayres, Philip W. (Philip Wheelock), 1861-1945; Bean, E. A.; Braman, R. A.; Brown, William Robinson, 1875-1955; Butler, Ovid, 1880-; Collingwood, G. H. (George Harris), 1890-1958; Dana, Samuel Trask, 1883-1978; De Carteret, S. L.; Downman, R. H.; Foster, John H. (John Harold), 1880-1956; Greeley, William Buckhout, 1879-1955; Gregory, H. S.; Hall, William Leroy, 1847-; Hollis, Allen; Hosmer, Ralph S. (Ralph Sheldon), 1874-1963; Long, Robert Alexander, 1850-1934; Pack, Charles Lathrop, 1857-1937; Potter, Albert Franklin, 1859-; Pratt, George D. (George Dupont), 1869-1935; Rathbun, Lawrence A.; Ridsdale, P. S.; Sterling, Ernest Albert, 1878-; Tennant, Emerson D.; New Hampshire. Forestry and Recreation Commission
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1909-1958; Series I; 1; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains files arranged in chronological order.
  - 1909-1928 June (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
  - 1928 July-1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 11-20)
- TOPICAL FILES, 1911-1955; Series II; 2; (5 boxes)
  This series contains files arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - American Forestry Association
    - Annual Reports, 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Bulletin, 1930-1937, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Declaration of policy and principles, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - General memoranda, 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - American Pulpwood Association, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brown Company, 1914-1938 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brown, William Robinson, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Conference of Lumber and Timber Products Industries
    - Preliminary report, 1933 October-1934 January (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Interim documents and summary, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Forest Conservation Congress, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - German Forestry material, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Kennebee Valley Protective Association, 1913-1920 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - National Forestry Conference, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - National Lumber Manufacturer's Association, 1917-1918; 1933 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - New England Forestry Foundation reports, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - New Hampshire Disaster Emergency Salvage
    - 1938 September-November (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
    - 1938 December-1939 Apr, undated (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
  - New Hampshire Forestry Commission
    - Budget material, 1917-1943 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Coos County material, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Forest Fire material, 1911-1919 (Box 4, Folder 43-45)
    - Fox Forest notes, 1950-1955 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Hearings on State forests, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Indentures and agreements, 1911-1938 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Legislative material, 1925-1941 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Reports, minutes and fire insurance data, 1912-1952 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Miscellanea, 1940-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 51-57)
  - New Hampshire Timberland Owners Association, 1911-1924 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Northeast Forestry Institute Report, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Northeastern Forest Research Council
    - Minutes, 1924-1932 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Reports, 1945-1948 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Miscellanea, 1924-1955 (Box 6, Folder 62-65)
  - Northeastern Forest Experiment Station
    - Annual Investigative program, 1928-1933 (Box 6, Folder 66-67)
    - Annual report, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Experiments, 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Forest investigation, 1925, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 70-71)
    - Organizational papers, 1924-1940 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Permanent sample plots, 1926-1927 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Technical notes, 1930-1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Society of American Foresters, 1931-1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Society for the Protection of New Hampshire Forests, 1911-1949, undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Swedish Forestry law, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - United States Chamber of Commerce, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - United States Federal Government
    - Legislative material, 1927-1953 (Box 7, Folder 79-81)
    - Publications, 1932-1934, undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - United States World War I Forestry Relief
    - Organizational material, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Publicity, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Reconstruction, 1917-1919 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - 10th and 20th Forestry Regiments, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Vermont Timberland Owners Association, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Weidman's Heil, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Miscellanea
    - Aerial photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Documents, undated (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Minutes, undated (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 92)
- MANUSCRIPTS, 1909-1952; Series III
  - Writings
    - Published, 1917-1950 (Box 9, Folder 93-94)
    - Unpublished, 1909-1952, undated (Box 9, Folder 95-98)
  - Our Forest Heritage
    - Manuscript A (Box 9, Folder 99-105)
    - Manuscript A (Box 10, Folder 106)
    - Manuscript B (Box 10, Folder 107-111)
    - Manuscript C (Box 10, Folder 112-115)
    - Manuscript D (Box 11, Folder 116-120)
    - Preliminary Galleys (Box 11, Folder 121-125)
    - Final Galleys (Box 12, Folder 126-131)
    - Notes (Box 12, Folder 132-135)
    - Notes (Box 13, Folder 136-137)
    - Photographs (Box 13, Folder 138)